bega.de 2016-10-15

# Privacy Policy · BEGA

## General privacy policy

The protection and security of your personal data are of primary importance to us. Accordingly we observe the statutory regulations in order to provide the best possible protection for your data. Below we would like to inform you about the type, scope and purpose of the data collection and its use:

BEGA Gantenbrink-Leuchten KG (hereinafter “BEGA”) collects, processes and uses personal data as defined by Section 3 Sub-section 1 of the German Data Protection Act (BDSG) solely within the scope of the BDSG and data covered by Sections 11 to 15a of the Telemedia Act (TMG) solely within the scope of these regulations.

 **1\. Data collection and storage**

On its website, BEGA offers a public area and a non-public (access-protected) area (“BEGA.com user area”) which pose different requirements on use (see the terms and conditions of use). Accordingly there are also differences in the collection and processing of personal data.

 **a. Public area**

i. When the public area of the website is used, the user’s automatically anonymised IP address is saved. As the result of the anonymisation, assignment is generally impossible and tracking the movement of the anonymised user on the website enables no conclusions to be drawn regarding a certain user. 

ii. In the public area of the website the user can create a so-called reminder list. BEGA uses so-called session ID cookies to save this list. Cookies are small text files which save the settings of websites, e.g. in the user’s web browser, in the course of using the website. The cookies are used to save user-related information and enable the user to create reminder lists. The session ID cookies used by BEGA are saved solely for the current session in the user’s web browser and are deleted automatically when the browser is closed.

iii. The Piwik open-source analysis tool, which saves a cookie on the user’s hard disk for seven days, is used for the collection of statistical data concerning the use of this website, e.g. to collect data about how often which products are placed on product reminder lists. No personal data are collected when the statistical data are transferred. All data are saved on the servers of BEGA Gantenbrink-Leuchten KG in Germany.

The user has the opportunity to object to the collection of his – already anonymised – user behaviour by entering or removing a checkmark at a respective position to deactivate or activate the Piwik analysis. This results in an opt-out cookie from Piwik being saved or deleted. In this way the user can decide whether an explicit advertising analysis cookie is allowed to be placed in his browser in order to enable the operator of the website to collect and analyse various statistical data. 

**b. BEGA.com user area**

i. BEGA saves the data entered in the registration form for the BEGA.com user area (e-mail address, password, title, sex, first name, surname, industry sector, company name, address, house number, postcode, town, country, phone number, fax number, mobile phone number, website) in a database which is hosted by a technical service provider in Germany. The data to be entered here are those referred to in Section 3 Sub-section 1 BDSG.

ii. Use of the BEGA.com user area requires the user to allow the session ID cookies used by BEGA and to permit the saving of data by session storage. In addition, a so-called “cross-site request forgery token” is employed to prevent the multiple-page falsification of your entered data, and the Piwik analysis tool is used (see above). 

iii. As a result of the registration, the user is able to create so-called project lists. These are then saved in a database and can be called up as long as the user account exists. 

iv. Every successful user authentication attempt is saved by BEGA in a database. After successful user authentication, the session is also saved and a cookie with the session ID is sent to the user’s browser. After successful logout, the session is deleted from the server.

v. When sending a so-called project list, the user has the opportunity to choose whether a sales partner pre-selected by BEGA and responsible for the territory where the project is taking place will receive the project list data and the user’s contact data (opt-in). Such an arrangement is not made without the user’s active choice.

 **2\. Use of the data**

a. The data entered by the user upon registration are used solely for the purpose of performing the functions offered on the BEGA website and carrying out the contract of use. As such, the data are used solely for internal purposes of customer administration and for processing enquiries from the holder of the account.

b. When BEGA is contracted by users to provide services or to supply products, it is necessary under certain circumstances to forward personal data such as names and addresses to companies which BEGA uses to provide a service or deliver a product.   
User data are not disclosed to third parties unless the user gives his express consent. The forwarding of personal data to governmental institutions and authorities takes place only within the scope of statutory regulations.

 **3\. Right of information and revision; withdrawal; blocking and deletion**

Users can contact BEGA at any time in writing or by e-mail to ask which of their personal data have been saved by BEGA. BEGA will try to answer as soon as possible depending on the volume. Incorrect data will be changed when the user sends notice to the above address.

Users who have given permission to use their personal data can withdraw their consent at any time. This requires no reason to be given. 

Similarly, users are free to have their saved personal data blocked or deleted. In this case the user must contact BEGA with concrete specification of the data to be deleted or blocked. Irrespective of that, all individual user data will be deleted automatically by BEGA when the user account is deleted by the user. Only the anonymised access data collected via Piwik will be retained.

BEGA is entitled for the reasons listed in the terms and conditions of use to block the authorisation of access to the BEGA.com user area by deactivation of the user account by an administrator and even to delete it completely. In the case of blocking, the previously collected data will not be deleted automatically but only on request of the user concerned. BEGA reserves the right to place the e-mail address of the blocked user on a so-called blacklist, preventing him from re-registering with this e-mail address.

 **4\. Address for enquiries, in particular in connection with Item 3**

Any enquiry or request related to personal data, including, but not limited to, enquiries in connection with the aforementioned Item 3\. (information, blocking, deletion, withdrawal of permission) must be sent by the user to the following address:

BEGA Gantenbrink-Leuchten KG   
Postfach 31 60   
58689 Menden, Germany   
– or –   
info@bega.com
